I've seen many organizations today
taking their nicely structured data from
an document database formulation or
graph database turn it into text
documents chunk it up and chug it into
vector which is insane. If you have
already well structured data why would
you turn it into stupid text and turn it
into vector embeddings which are
completely okay.
Tell us a little bit about Neo forj.
It's a very interesting technology that
really shows graph databases and what
graph databases.
Yeah. So you connect information right
so you connect people events processes
products so you can do traditional use
cases like supply chain software
analytics cyber security and other
things unlike in relation other
databases that compute connections
between information at query time and in
graph database we persist it at
insertion time. So we basically
materialize these relationships as fifth
class citizens in the database and then
when it comes to querying we just follow
pointers in the database. Interesting
actually because it actually carries
intent, doesn't it? The relationships
show if you care about a relationship
between two nodes. That's an intent that
that is something that is important to
the business. You care about the
business.
[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI native dev. And joining me today,
a great old friend from many many years.
We're talking we were talking about 15
years or so. Michael Hunger, developer
advocate, head of developer advocacy at
uh
actually I moved to product now of
product innovation. Wow. So I'm doing
all the cool new stuff, the shiny
things. I can basically see how how you
integrate like all the modern
developments especially geni today but
also like cloud integrations and so on
into the graph database right how that's
awesome
use basically what I've been doing even
in de for a long time with new labs and
so on
but now like officially in in the
product or and driving a lot of these
innovation topics.
Oh that's great. That's great. Well,
that that goes to show we didn't meet
today, right?
And and and yeah, I'm still here at AI
AI Focus here in in in Stockholm and and
yeah, I bumped into I bumped into
Michael both in the corridor and also in
the keynote. Um you've been at Neo Forj
for like I say 15 years or so as well.
Um tell us a little bit about Neo forj
because this is it's it's it's it's a
very interesting kind of like technology
that really shows graph databases and
what graph databases. So graph databases
many people basically know relation
databases where you have rows and
columns and tables but in a graph
database you have nodes and
relationships or entities and
relationships basically what you would
draw on a whiteboard right so you have
c circles and arrows between them and
then you can put arbitrary information
on the entities but also on relationship
which is actually quite important
and you connect information right so you
connect people events processes products
whatever right so you can do traditional
use cases like supply chain software
analytics cyber security and other
things. Um, and what's actually
especially interesting that unlike in
relation to other databases that compute
connections between information at query
time and in graph database we persist it
at insertion time. So we basically
materialize these relationships as first
class citizens in in the database and
then when it comes to querying we just
follow pointers in the data which makes
it much much faster for these complex
queries as such right. So, NEJ has been
around for a long time. It's been open
source database for a long time. It has
Swedish roots as well. So, it come from
Mamm Sweden actually. Okay.
Um and uh so and now we've of course
expanded globally. But I joined when we
were 10 people like
wow
seven streets a Brit and American and me
really sounds like the start of a joke
that doesn't
suit
they went into a bar and and
and they kick over some tables right
and all of and all of us and all of a
sudden they form relationships and graph
databases were born there we go um so
yeah I expect no one laughed at that in
on the on the audience just then but but
we but we laughed so that's that's the
important thing so so yeah graph
databases have been around a long time
people who care about the relationships
between nodes, the relationships between
data which is very very hard to
essentially almost like you're forcing
it in relation in a relational data.
It's quite a pain. Have you tried this
ever?
I mean you know object relational
database mis impedance mismatch right?
So that's like even there's even a term
for it whenever you try to take a rich
domain model and shoehorn it into
relation it's always painful right so
and busy in a graph it's more natural
and it's also what's interesting you
don't lose the business people because
in a relation database if I show a
business person like 250 tables they say
okay what do you want to tell me but if
you show them basically connected
information on the screen how all the
things go together then say oh I see and
you missed this relationship here by the
way something like that so you take also
the the the the people from the business
side along which makes them for much
richer development experience as well.
It's interesting. It's interesting
actually because it actually carries
intent, doesn't it? The relationships
show if you care about a relationship
between two nodes, that's an intent that
that is something that is important to
the business. Okay, you care about the
business
and because you can put attributes on
relationships as well. You can actually
score this intent. You can even put
weights and and and scores and things
like that on that as well or like time
frames, right? So if you have certain
relationships that only exist in a
certain time frame then you can
basically put this information on on it
as well which you then can use for
recommendation for for detection and
other things as well. Yeah. The the not
just the attributes on the entities are
important but also how are they
connected and when and how strongly are
they also connected. Magenta is actually
even further into graph algorithms and
stuff like that. They go into page rank
and clustering and like all the other
things
to see how close nodes are and things.
Exactly. Or how important one node is in
in the network. For instance, if you
have something like a fraudster and they
have a really high centrality, that
means they had a lot of already
influence in this in this. But if they
have really low scores uh uh centrality
scores, then they have not started their
fraud business yet. So you can catch
them before the fact basically.
Yeah. Yeah. Oh, cool.
So there's
and of course graph databases have been
around
for a while. for a while. They're not
they're not like, you know,
I mean, I still love it and I'm still
excited about it, but you know, we've
been around for a while and people have
been using Neforj for a long time.
Yeah. In just in their normal
applications where where the
relationships between data is important,
graph databases are a great way to
implement that and then use that within
your application. However,
now AI has come along.
Everything has changes. And now I
mentioned you got you got two sessions.
But one was about how um graph databases
can help you particularly in and around
the rag space and actually pulling
context in whereby if you you know get
some kind of a prompt you can actually
take you can actually understand
relationships between between what you
know what you're hitting in in your in
your in your rag database equivalent. Um
and as a result you can actually pull
various bits of context that are
actually uh adjacently important.
Exactly.
right and the surroundings are
important, right? Not just the exact
like thing that you get back from your
vector search or something like that,
but actually what's surrounding it? How
does it connect to the context of the
user who's actually asking the question,
how does it connect to the business uh
processes and other things, right? So,
so you get much richer answer uh back
from the database which you then pass to
the LLM for the final.
Amazing.
So, I'd love to talk about that and then
you then you go on later this afternoon
to talk about MCP. my other favorite my
other one of my other favorite topics
and specifically about how devs and dev
tools can be used with MCP to
effectively make developers more
productive. So I really want to focus on
that as well. But let's talk about let's
talk about how you can use graph
databases in in Iraq. I guess to start
off with
when we use when we we kind of like you
know use more traditional kind of like
not traditional we're only a few years
in right but you know non graphics based
rag basic rag um
what I think most people know how kind
of like you know people use rag today
what are the what are the downfalls
there what are the what are the pitfalls
that actually say do you know what this
isn't this isn't good enough we need we
need to be better here
yeah actually it's kind of interesting
so I was at AI engineering uh conference
yesterday last week in San Francisco San
Francisco
and they actually put up an rag
assistant uh using vector search of
their conference and right
and I tried to find my talk putting in
my name it didn't find anything okay
I was talking to bunch of people for
Microsoft about MCP and they had a talk
as well and said basically show me all
the talks for Microsoft and NCP and it
didn't show anything right so it didn't
show me two other talks but not the one
that I I came for
so what I want to say is basically
vector search of content where you only
have fragments of of content has a bunch
of downfalls. One is it's a black box,
right? So you basically vector search
but you don't know why and how you
actually get these responses. The other
thing is also it doesn't take context
into account right so it doesn't take in
account like like MCP is actually a
topic and this topic is connected to
other talks right so even if it didn't
find the talk in the first vector search
it could actually via the context of MCT
pull the other talks in for instance
right so and then uh from that
perspective that's something where if
you only limit yourself to the text
fragments you're losing out on a lot of
information that's actually in your data
right so most people have actually more
than documents they have like already
structured data they have semuctured
data and lots of other data sources And
what was interesting actually one of the
examples you gave in the keynote was so
I think it was about similar to like a
company that has maybe it was putting in
um it had an issue or something like
that and and it was a ticket that was
raised other things like well what other
tickets have been raised on this same
topic. What other tickets has the
company raised? And you can al you can
all all of a sudden based on a request
start getting a huge amount of context
not just about the text string but about
about the individual the company the the
the relationship the customer look at
the customer for instance from from the
input you don't just look at the
question string but you also look at the
customer who's asking it and you
actually look at what have the what has
the customer actually deployed and what
is enabled and then and so on and then
you tie it back to the to support case
and say okay have they already asked
previously similar support cases perhaps
it's in subsequent follow up error or
something like that
maybe they've tried other fixes and
actually you won't go through that
so you understand the full story it's
basically like you could almost say like
a customer 360 they see the full story
unfolding and then uh basically the
customer support agent and the LLM can
basically take this rich information and
craft a much more personalized and more
relevant answer for this and the other
thing that's really important is when
you just get these text fragments back
from a ve vector index it's basically
black box right so you get it back but
you can't explain why and how it came
back. But in a graph you can actually
point to oh we fetch this information
and this is why we fetch it because
exactly this relationship exists and
because the score on these relationships
is higher than X and and so on. So you
can also if someone is interested in the
kind of why you can basically show them
where did it come from why was it what
why was it retrieved and and and so on.
So basically also have this
explanability which in some industries
is also important for auditing or for
regulatory purposes or just because I
want to know it didn't answer my
question well then I want to know what
was actually missing and it might
actually be that in your source data one
relationship was missing that usually
connects some stuff but in your data
import it was uh you know didn't come
in.
Yeah. And this was interesting actually
because in in in your session you did
you did kind of like show if you was to
look into you know normal rag you'd
essentially just see a whole bunch of
floating point kind of like numbers
negative numbers vectors make sense of
them I can't no it's it's basically a
binary file it might as well be a binary
file whereas from the rag point of view
you'll actually see what do you see do
you actually see the nodes and the
relationships and things like that
exactly you can show them if your
application or your assistant
uh or agent supports this then you can
basically say oh I want to drill down
and I want to see the details you click
on a link and then shows you basically
the visualization of what information
was pulled in and how is it related
basically
so from an eval point of view then who
would who who would would there be a
role a person who would look at a
general request and then say right okay
I can see I know what context should be
here
but it's not how do I then actually make
changes to this
exactly so for instance when you had uh
an a system then you get get a useful
feedback uh or you basically either
active or or indirect feedback then you
see okay these answers should actually
be coming from the system why are they
not coming from the system and then you
can basically drill down and say
basically what is happening here why are
the users not happy then you can
actually see oh there was actually a
whole part of the information that we
have in the system was actually missing
because it was disconnected or it was
not uh found in the index but if there
was a relationship here we could
actually fetch it through this as well
right and then And then uh if you set
real eval pipelines up then you would
basically say as part of my eval scoring
then you can compare for the lower
scoring ones kind of what what's missing
in in the structure and you can also
have this interactive for the end user
where you basically say okay the end
user can actually drill down and say see
what is actually behind this answer
right so and then you can go further and
and basically investigate more for
instance or basically follow ask
follow-up questions that follow the the
context
yeah interesting how would you how would
you populate that then because like
obviously with with you know a regular
you know pine cone or something I just
kind of like throw stuff at it and just
think okay that'll hopefully that'll
hopefully do
exactly that's there's a mix of stuff
right so for for once many people
already have structured data right and
and that's actually something that I my
my toenails almost roll up so I've seen
many organizations today taking their
nicely structured data from an document
database or relational or graph database
turn it into text documents chunk it up
and chunk just chug it into vector index
which is insane. If you have already
well structured data, why would you turn
it into stupid text and turn it into
vector embeddings which are completely
opaque?
So one is the the structured data that
you already have which might be your you
know your customers your projects your
employees your processes whatever
and then also the unstructured data that
you get from from PDF documents from
research reports from customer tickets
and and so on. So you basically use the
structured data and the unstructured
data together and for the unstructured
data actually LLMs are also super
helpful. In the old days we did a lot of
NLP Stanford NLTK and like all the other
stuff but now actually LLMs are so good
at at extraction and language skills
that you can provide them a schema
and instructions and the text and it
will actually extract entities and
relationships and attributes from
even from unstructured data.
Yeah, even from and that's actually
pretty cool.
I was going to say how accurate is that
though? Will it try and create
as usual? As usual it's not perfect,
right? So you get perhaps an 80%
sometimes 90% rate but it's still better
than having a human go through it
manually
and then you can also do multipass and
there's lots of ways of how to improve
this as well.
I suppose I suppose a failure there
would be it's adding context that isn't
relevant so it's actually not as big a
problem.
Exactly. But that's something because
you have the schema already you can just
validate against the existing schema and
drop the stuff that you're not
interested in. So from that perspective
you also have means to improve it. And
then there's like things like entity
solution and other things. There's also
graph algorithms that you can run then
at the end on on top of stuff and say
okay these five simments are actually
the same sim and we merge it together at
one and things like that.
Interesting.
Let's switch gears a little bit. Let's
talk about MCP the hot topic right MCP.
So interestingly so so first of all why
did you pick MCP from a dev point of
view as in a dev tooling point of view
versus an app point of view? It's a
really interesting one because I was um
so I started out with MCP actually early
December. So Anthropic published their
blog post and the the framework or the
the spec in late November like last week
of November and I built the first MCP
server for NEFJ in early December like
first or second week of December
and so initially it was like data right
so just looking at data but then I
thought about oh actually you know this
data also has metadata it also has a
schema. So as a deaf I can use the
schema to for instance generate
graphical type definitions or Java
classes or Python pyantic classes. And
then it got me thinking okay if I have
this
and I can use MCP to wrap it around APIs
could I also wrap um basically
infrastructure APIs with an MCP server
right and then I saw that some other
folks like Cloudflare and others have
done this as well. So you can spin up
cloud fire workers with MCP. And so I
basically built another MCP server that
wraps the Nej cloud uh APIs basically
where you can provision databases and
scale up and scale down databases and
stuff like that behind the MCP server.
and then they turn an out. It's actually
really nice if you if you're in your IDE
and just say, "Hi, I'm in cursor. Give
me my instance. Scale up this instance
to something. Oh, I need a quick test
instance." And basically as part of your
chat behind the scenes, it can go off
and do stuff. And then you saw more and
more of these kind of def MCP servers
popping up like for instance the GitHub
server where you can then say oh
actually I need uh some uh I want to use
this library and I don't have the doc so
f fetch the lmtxt from this GitHub repo
and and it will go this using the MCP
tool right so as a dev
and I mean you've used your share of CLI
tools from the cloud provider and from
all kinds of other infrastructure
providers there's a lot to learn and
remember right so like all the API with
all the um individual commands and all
the other stuff and no one wants to
remember this kind of stuff because
that's not really valuable knowledge,
right? So the same is you don't want to
go into some crappy AWS UI and click
together some services or something like
that, right? Why shouldn't I be able to
do this in the context of my code where
actually there's a much richer in
understanding of what do I want to
deploy? Why and where do I want to
deploy it? What are like you know um
what's my uh infrastructure setup in
terms of like test staging? How many uh
test runners do I need to do load
testing on this which is all in the in
the environment configuration of my
project anyway?
If I connect this to the MC to the def
MCP servers that wrap the infrastructure
APIs then I can basically actually make
much better decisions than if I go in
isolation to these APIs or or CLIs and
need to reproduce through the human mind
all the
you're more likely to miss something if
you go in and do it manually.
Exactly. Right. And then you can just
tell it and say hey like for instance
with cloud code or so I just connect MCP
servers and say basically just in my
interaction oh and I need to spin up a
test database for this or can you write
an integration test or for instance I
had recently one where I basically said
okay we need to build this application
but I want you to test run all the
queries that we built in this
application against the real test
database. So while it was generating the
code, it at the same time took the
queries that were part of the server
basically or the service and test ran it
against the test database. So that
validated that the queries were all
corrected and generated. So it's also
kind of a self uh selfcorrection self
evaluation part that you give the LLM
the code generating LLM as well. Not
just llinter and compiler like you have
for code but you can also do this on the
infrastructure level for your databases
for your cloud API.
So where do you do it? Do you do you
mostly do it in the infrastructure
layers or to to help you create and
presumably this is dev time only?
So these are dev time and and perhaps
deployment and and devops and and
management time as well.
Um yeah so those are mostly deaf time
ones. Yeah
we also have like the whole data MCP for
agents and so on which is kind of yet
another topic as such right. But I found
this really interesting because you know
bringing all these things together
basically for a deaf is almost like an
you have this uh really like a toolbox
basically right so where right or in the
in the past all these infrastructure uh
services were kind of in silos in
isolation right so they didn't really
work together and even in a service like
AWS or so you still see that they're
kind of siloed and everything is kind of
its own universe in a way right so and
but in your uh in your assistant
basically all the things come together
as an as an as tools basically and then
the assistant actually creates this
almost like federation layer across them
if you think about it right so and then
and it takes the context of your code
and your project into account plus the
instructions and the conversations that
you have and so it has a much richer
interactions and it can cross things
right for instance it could take
information from let's say um
your your CI/CD run and generate new
integration tests from it or it can
basically take information from your
from your cloud database and use this to
spin up a new container somewhere in an
environment to to do something, right?
So, it basically can also cross systems
basically without you having to copy
over stuff from
as long as because it's a gentic and
it's kind of like making
and the context in your on your in your
um IDE basically, right? So, it's not
that you have to move this somewhere,
but it's like in super rich context
that's in as part of your
and without it, it's that frustration of
I'm going to have an interaction with an
LLM. It it says something but it can't
do it itself. It tells me the steps that
I need to do.
Exactly. And then please go ahead and
copy paste and then you become the the
junior dev who copies and past stuff to
to a form in I don't know in cloud run
or in in in EC2 or something
and then there's an error. So I have to
copy paste the error.
Exactly. Why should I do it itself?
Right. And then and then you can also
start to you know initially it might be
manually interactive in the conversation
but then you can also tell cloud code
whatever we just did there turn it into
a script or CI/CD pipeline or something
like that right so and then then it
basically migrates something that you
manually jointly developed into
basically running code into
auto let's talk about security
um actually my previous job was sneak
I've lived security for six years and
continue to do so of But but as my as my
role, I've lived security for six years
and now I do it as a as because I want
to because I enjoy it. Um let's talk
about security with MCP service.
Actually, you mentioned the GitHub MCP
server. Uh just recently there was an
very interesting I think who was it
weeks ago, last week there was like an
interesting
Yeah. Did you see that
injection attack?
Yeah, that's right. That's right. It
needed a bit of a setup in the sense
Well, it didn't need that much of a
setup.
Not not much actually. No, a user has a
user has an MCP uh server available, a
GitHub MCP server available to the
official one. Yeah, the official one.
Um they have uh a private and a public
repo. They ask something of the public
repo. You know, maybe take a look at my
issues and fix as many issues as you can
or or or you know,
solve as many issues as you can.
Something that actually is is not
it's a it's a use case. It's a common
use case of a GitHub MTP server. But if
a malicious user adds an issue um uh to
the public repo asking
you know something malicious I want grab
as much information private information
about whatever it can be as it can be as
blatant as it wants to be.
Um then that MCP server will go actually
yeah I do have access to this user's
other private repos. I'll grab that and
as a result of trying to fix or solve it
actually creates a pull request back on
that public repo um with that p with
that private information from the
private repo and starts and starts
edited the read me before the private
repact. Yes. Yes. That's what that was
the example was it adds the readme and
and it's it's information leak from a
private repo. How do we and it's really
the authorization
uh circumventing that authorization that
a user does that user have authorization
to access that data
the user has authorization for both
right so and basically delegate this
authorization to the MCP server so the
MCP server acts in the users state but
the MCP server itself
is not problematic because it just
basically is API access right so we have
API access today
the problematic thing is just that the
LLM can't discern learn from what is
data to process and instructions.
So the data and control plane emerge.
Exactly. And that's one of the big
challenges that we need to solve in AI
systems anyway. Yes.
So not just in MCP and and and and
coding assistance but it's a general
problem that currently data and
instructions are not separate. Yeah. So
I hope that the model providers uh will
start tagging actually different things.
So that basically instructions that are
coming from the user and are validated
and verified are tagged as instructions
and the other things are tacked as
processing data.
Yeah.
And then the LLM will treat or that's
actually the ideal would treat the
instructions as instructions and the
rest just as processing. There's a
number of approaches that different
people have proposed where you can do
this today already where you have
basically almost like an hierarchy of um
LLMs that process stuff. So where you
basically say okay the lowest level
processing LLMs they see the data and
they get an instruction but what they
return is not plain text to the upper
level LMS which could be interpreted as
instructions again but they just
basically generate tokens or file names
or something like that where basically
they just hand pointers and then the the
the content of this is actually not um
processed in the LLM but just for
instance shown on the UI. So it's
basically something that goes as on a
side channel not through the LM but on a
side channel and then the UI would just
show it like you would do in a normal
UI. So that's one way of how you can
circumvent things like that or where you
say okay the lower level LLM does just
data processing but it's not allowed uh
to basically ex exit its scope basically
where you scope the LLM that it can only
do something for instance in the public
pro project and can't access this other
information. So it's about like a mix of
so the the the root problem is data and
instructions are on the same level which
is kind of
you had the separation of this in
computer since architecture basically
right so so that's one challenge and the
other one is kind of how are things
scoped and who has access to what right
so you need some kind of like sandboxing
almost for those right so and that's
really not just related to MCP even if
you use if you was you would use um
let's say API calls would do the exactly
the same Right. So, it's more like an
LLM problem than an MCP problem. It just
makes it much much easier with MCP
because MCP now opens up all these
services and like Lego blocks you can
combine them. And I mean, the first rule
would of course only use trusted MCP
servers.
This was what this was one of the things
I was going to say cuz it kind of like
reminds me a little bit of almost like
open source components, right? You still
need to do your due diligence. You need
to recognize who they're coming from. Uh
and it's like otherwise we're just going
to start adding
potentially dangerous things into into
that can actually not just dangerous
things they they can perform actions
right and they can describe
so it's software supply chain again
it is it's exactly
look at snook also entail right so
software supply chain attacks and things
like that and I think this whole area is
still growing up right and that's why I
would also say
you should also basically limit and
sandbox where use this kind of stuff,
right? So, for instance, in really
mission critical areas, I would try to
avoid using all the bleeding engine
things, but only use like things where
you as human actually copy and paste
stuff from A to B. Yeah.
Which is safer than basically running it
as automation. And I would more do it
more in the exploration phase where you
basically try out new things and and so
on on harmless projects where you work
where everything is an open source
project. So for instance, what I do when
I uh I use these kind of GitHub
integrations, I only give it access to
my open source repos. I don't I never
give it access to my private repos
because I I don't want to accidentally
leak something or sometime sometimes I
just create another user GitHub user
that has only access to the
public repos uh if it does not work with
the uh tokens, right? So and and and
that's where for implementation you want
to basically
be in a space that's really like a open
sandbox right
and I think that's the core you're what
you're doing is you're you're rely
you're putting the security the
authorization in the hands of a
deterministic
uh model
something that has strong authorization
and authentication built in
you're not providing the data to the LLM
and make and allowing the LM to make
that decision as to what is and what
isn't.
reasonable to put out
or you separate the or you separate the
processing right so the processing
happens in kind of sandbox environments
and then the results of that are taken
basic really just as data and would
basically imagine you would say okay
let's process these issues it would not
go through the LLM but it would just
basically do an create issue call with
the content that was generated but the
content would never be looked at by the
LLM but it would be just passed into the
API call as as something so it would
never be able to use this as an
instruction basically right so and
that's where the the sandboxing of these
individual parts comes in but it's an
interesting space and I think the
security you know people say where's the
S in MCP right
oh is that the new that's the new
version of the S in IoT stands for
security
and I mean it's also really I I I love
that people try to find these kind of
loopholes and injection attacks and so
on because that helps making stuff
better but that's also a little bit of
an arms race right so
so it's also fun to watch in Anyway, and
and but with all the new technologies,
you have these things and and we need to
uh sort out the kinks of new.
Sounds good. Let's give some practical
advice to developers out there in terms
of which MCP servers they should be
considering. Um what's what's what's on
your list of things that you use maybe
at Neo Forj or that you've seen people
use that you think, oh wow, that looks
that looks pretty cool. That actually
really helped.
Uh so for me, uh the extended thinking
MCP server for entropic is actually
quite useful. Yeah.
Then Anthropic added an MCP server that
is like in memory MCP server which is
actually quite cool. Um which basically
can take information from you store it
in actually interestingly they picked a
knowledge graph as an representation. So
we built a Neo version of that which
actually can start accumulating
information from conversations into an
structured data structure and which you
could even share across a team. So
imagine you as a team are working on
something and uh you know for instance
you're working on on project specs or so
right? So then the information from the
conversation could be extracted and
added to this joint uh you know
knowledge base in a way. So that's
something really interesting.
The other ones that have been using is
mostly the the stock ones like
Cloudflare and and and and GitHub and
Slack a little bit. Notion as well.
Actually I learned last week about Pipe
which is like an integrator for MCP
servers. They have like 2,700 or so MCP
servers. Of course, they have many other
registries and I saw last week as well
that um MRA AI the agent JavaScript tool
they have actually an MCP registry
registry. I mean really it's insane. Um
but uh Pep Pep I found interesting
because they basically allow you as
application builder to quickly integrate
a bunch of MCP servers that they
actually validate and partially also
self-host as well. So you have like a
curated version of like you have like
the the the notions, the slacks, the
sales forces and and and so on as MCP
servers and and that's something that
might be actually quite quite nice if
you build a integration and stuff. But
what I actually would recommend build
your own,
right? So, you know, take your own
whatever you're working on, your own
APIs or your own infrastructure and just
get a much better understanding of how
MCP works by building your own MCP
server like adding a bunch of tools and
prompts and and resources. So, you have
a much better firsthand understanding
what's actually happening behind the
scenes because I think that's one of the
dangers. If everything is like a black
box and magic
then either you don't trust it at all
because it's black box or you blindly
trust it and and neither side is is is a
good place to be right. Yeah,
I always said in the past if you make
conscious decision informed decisions by
having learned before you make the
decision then it's much better decisions
right so and actually building MCP
servers is not hard today you can use
first MCP or so and it takes
I don't know an hour or two to do one
you can either wipe code it if you want
to but it's it's you know it's 200 lines
of code or so and and that's actually
something that gives you much better
understanding of MCPS
yeah and I think also there's a ton of
validation style things as well that we
can kind of like add in. I know sneak
for example an MCP server. You can just
kind of say any any security issues in
my code. It'll go off run sneak code I
think and it will it will provide you
information based on that. Um another
interesting one that I've I've I've
looked at is uh context 7 which I've
heard a ton of people talk about whereby
it actually gives you a more accurate
code generation. So um if if you're if
you're I don't know if I'm coding
against a certain version of something
rather than just try and get huge
amounts of information and try and try
and you know base uh the the code
suggestions to me on every version that
I could be using it recognizes oh okay I
need to go to this version of the docs
or this version of the API and I'll only
provide you suggestions from those so it
can kind of make that more accurate in
terms of the suggestions. There's a ton
of them out there.
I heard about ref. My a friend of mine
recommended ref to me. Okay,
ref is also an MCP server or and service
that provides LLM optimized
documentation for different uh tools and
libraries basically. So it basically
like an LLM txt for each of these kind
of frameworks like they have a few
hundred frameworks that they support.
That's also an interesting one as such.
What could be actually really
interesting from the security angle is
if you think about proxy MCP servers,
right? So one MCP server that proxies
another one and actually does filtering
of the content that goes through. That
could be really interesting. So you
basically add a layer of security on the
ingoing data where you can basically
validate certain things within third
party service
like exactly. So that will be an
interesting one and I think we will see
more and more that companies will
establish these MCP kind of gateways
almost where they have like these are
the allowed MCP servers in our
organization. We add these kind of
security authorization controls and also
like filter and validation. what can we
let go out into the world of the MCP
tools and what not
kind of feel it feels like almost like
what um what Lira are doing from a from
a you know prompt point of view and and
and having guards on the input and
output to to and from an LLM but to MCPs
or something like that
it kind of feels a lot like uh in the
spirits of when GraphQL came out in
2016. So because there's now also like
the spec the working groups like
everyone is jumping on it. There's lots
of energy and lots of enthusiasm as well
and it's also open source. So I feel
very much reminded of back then when we
were at Facebook and the graph working
group and working with them and so that
was actually an good time and I feel
like same energy and also kind of same
same approach like a grassroots yeah
movement more right so yes there's a
proposal from from anthropic but then it
grows through all the people
contributing right and then the big
players were actually more or less
forced
to come on board by the developer ground
smell which is amazing right so when
how often do you have this that like
Google, you know, Microsoft, OpenAI and
the others are actually forced by
developer adoption to,
you know, join initiative. So that so
it's like FOMO for the big ones where
it's usually the other way around. So
it's actually quite
quite cool.
Yeah.
Awesome. Michael, I got you know, I got
to run. I got I got I got a presentation
to give five minutes, right? I got I got
I got to run. Michael, absolute
pleasure. Absolute pleasure to see you
here again and um and we should do this
again. But thank you very much. And
yeah, if you're interested in in graph
databases particularly for for I think
you know the the rag style sounds super
interesting and I think very very
happy to reach out happy to chat and and
let me know if if you need any more. So
and otherwise we go and see if I I go
see you
I'll go sit down in the front row and
see how see how it goes. Yeah. All
right. Thanks very much and thanks all
for listening. Tune in to the next
episode.
Take care.
[Music]